the trade that you see on the screen is
one of the most profitable ways that I
have found a trade in any market and
that is by trading Trend continuation
pullbacks and the reason these trades
are so profitable is because you can
normally get a very limited risk on
these trades with a potentially
unlimited reward if price does continue
in that Trend now there is a very
specific way to utilize these pullback
trades in order to make profit and there
are a few detrimental mistakes that most
Traders are making so that is why in
this video You're going to get a
complete guide to pullback trading you
are going to learn the top mistakes that
you must avoid in order to make money
from Trading pullbacks and you are going
to get a full rules-based trading
strategy that I utilized to get into the
trade you see on the screen right now
and that I use in my own trading on a
daily basis so if that sounds good then
go ahead and click that like button for
me go ahead and subscribe if you are new
and I'll be right back after the intro
and displayer
[Music]
welcome back and let's go ahead and get
started first by assessing what a
pullback actually is now in order to
understand that you have to understand
what a Candlestick chart is a
Candlestick chart is a visual
representation of the decisions made by
all Market participants on a specific
asset right now we're looking at the
candada Yen on the chart so what this
means on the Canada Yin is that we have
had more buyers than sellers when price
is pushing up to a new high we then have
a slow in demand for the Canada Yen
causing a pullback and that's all the
pullback is is a slow in demand followed
by buyers taking back control more
Market participants wanting to buy this
asset than sell it followed by yet again
another decrease in demand and this goes
on and on while we see prices in an
uptrend and these pullbacks occur due to
many things one of which is people that
bought down here are now going to be
taking profit the other is that other
Traders other Market participants may
think this is a great level for a
possible reversal and they may sell but
as long as buyers continue taking
control at higher prices than the
previous lows then we continue to have
an uptrend and obviously prices need to
break the previous highs for this to be
an uptrend as well but that's something
really important for you to understand
as we move forward in today's video so
with this being an uptrend what do you
think the best place to buy would be in
this uptrend well it's always going to
be the bottom of this pullback so what
we do in order to trade pullback
successfully is we wait on a
identifiable Trend that needs to be very
clear we'll talk more about that in just
a second we wait on this identifiable
Trend where prices are making higher
highs and higher lows we then wait for a
pullback and as this pullback is
happening we're trying to find the very
bottom of the pullback so what we want
to to do is wait for this pullback to
start and then wait for buyers to start
taking back control and when we have a
situation where price is in an
identifiable uptrend meaning we're
making higher highs along with higher
lows compared to the previous lows then
we wait for this pullback and also have
the patience to wait for buyers to start
taking back control that is when we give
ourselves the best odds of having
winning trades while trading pullbacks
now that was just the most simple
explanation of pullback trading that you
need to know before we move forward
throughout this video you are going to
learn how I find the bottom of pullbacks
in the most accurate way to provide me
with profitable trading opportunities
now before we dive into the full
strategy let's talk about the top
detrimental mistakes you must avoid
while trading pullbacks if you ever hope
to trade them profitably so the first
mistake is trading pullbacks when price
is not in Trend I see this all the time
a Trader will send me an email and go
hey look we have this push up and now we
have a pullback and we have buyers
taking back control should I buy here
the answer is no there is no Trend here
yes we had a push higher but when you're
trading pullbacks you want to trade the
pullback directly after a new high what
I mean by that is price would have
needed to create a brand new high
compared to this previous high before
you looking for a possible pullback
entry on this specific trade so a simple
rule of thumb for this is you always
want to be Trading a pullback after a
brand new high has been created as we
can see here pushup pullback pushup to
what a brand new high then we have a
pullback push up to another brand new
high followed by a pullback now is when
you can start looking for Possible
Trading opportunities after and I mean
directly after a brand new high this is
extremely important because it's what's
going to give us the best odds of
winning trades while we're trading
pullbacks the second biggest mistake I
see is Traders trying to place trades
using pullbacks without seeing buyers or
sellers taking back control at the end
of the pullback to give you an example
of that take a look at the chart now we
have a defined downtrend that's pretty
clear here we then have a pullback and
we have this little tiny red candle now
this would not be considered a lot of
selling pressure the body of this candle
is Tiny so this would not be the
confirmation I need I want to see that
sellers are really planning to Take Back
Control whenever I'm trying to trade the
top of a pullback in a downtrend so this
tiny candle would not be that this would
not be very good confirmation that
sellers are taking back control and not
waiting for that confirmation puts you
in a position to end up with a losing
trade and the third and final mistake
that I see most often is Traders trying
to take pullback trades too early and
with zero other Confluence so this would
be an example of that we have a nice
uptrend here followed by a pullback and
a green candle but this pullback is
really shallow not only that there's no
other confluences aligning with this
trade and when trading pullbacks with no
other Confluence you are very unlikely
to be profitable consistently so those
are the three mistakes you must avoid if
you want to be profitable trading
pullbacks now let me talk about how I
utilize pullbacks to actually Place
trades and what I'm going to be showing
you now is the most accurate way I found
to know when the end of the pullback is
going to occur I do this by utilizing a
full rules-based trading strategy that
you're to learn right now the first
trade we're going to look at is one
you've already seen at the very
beginning of this video on the Euro
Aussie and on this trade where price is
right now would you consider this to be
in a downtrend hopefully you were able
to say yes we have a very clear move
pushing lower making a new higher low
and a new lower low causing this to be
now in a downtrend so that is always the
first step in any trade this is
obviously a bearish version of this
trade where we would be looking for sell
trades with this Strat and the very
first step will always be identify the
trend of the market so in this case
we're in a downtrend now what's next I
obviously want to see the start of a
pullback if I'm going to find the top of
the pullback and try to place a sell
trade so we want to see a pullback start
now after this we're going to avoid that
second mistake I talked about by
combining this pullback with multiple
areas of Confluence so for me the most
important things I look at in my trading
are structure and Trend and since we
already have the trend identified the
next thing I want to do is look left and
find an area of structure that's been
tested multiple times so this is one of
the ways I identify where a pullback is
likely to end and what we're going to
start seeing sellers Take Back Control
in this market now that's not all I'm
looking for that's just the first two
steps of this strategy next up I want
this pullback to get very close to or
touch the 50 period exponential moving
average this moving average can act as
resistance in a downtrend as you can see
looking left and when combined with a
structure level that's been tested
multiple times it's shown to give me
more accurate trading opportunities so I
love it whenever I see this whenever I
see price coming to the 50 EMA while
also being at a level of structure
that's been tested multiple times while
also being in a confirmed downtrend this
is my best case scenario for possible
pullback trades and the way that I trade
the way that I create strategies is
through a process say that I call
C C stands for conditions which are all
the things I need to see before I look
for a possible entry reason when trading
a strategy and then obviously after the
conditions an entry reason followed by
stops and targets what you've just
learned the market being in an
identifiable Trend Market being at a
level of structure that's been tested
multiple times and the market pushing
against the 50 EMA would all fall under
the category of conditions now after
conditions I don't just Place random
trades what is it I said that I wanted
to see at the end of pullbacks so these
conditions are the first step but at the
end of pullbacks I want to see bears in
this case or sellers start taking back
control to show me that we have a high
likelihood of continuing this downtrend
because if Bears Never Take Back Control
then this could easily be a reversal and
markets could go higher but I want to
see a Candlestick pattern or a
combination of candlesticks that show me
bears are taking back control the way
that I do this and I'll zoom in to make
this easier to see but this is one of my
favorite ways to identify when bears
have taken back control after a pullback
so as you can see in this pullback we
have a couple of red candles you might
be saying well does that not mean that
bears are taking back control not for me
the rules-based way I identify this is
by looking at the bottom of the last
green candle of this pullback obviously
this is for bearish trades when we're
can get a downtrend and we have green
candles in our pullback I want to look
at the bottom of the last green candle
of that pullback and I want to wait for
a red candle to close below it now that
can happen in the very next candle that
can take a couple of candles that can
take up to three or four candles but
when a bearish candle closes below the
lowest point of the last bullish candle
and our pullback that's when I consider
that bears have now taken back control
and we're likely to see Trend
continuation after that and obviously
that's only after all the other
conditions I've discussed are met so in
this case on the Euro Aussie what did we
see well the very next candle as you can
see closed below the low of the last
green candle of the pullback again I
hope that's not confusing we have green
candles in our pullback as you can see
this is our last green candle this would
be the low of it this red candle did not
close below that low we then have
another green candle in our pullback
this is the low of that green candle
this red candle did not close below the
low of that green candle next up we have
this as the last green candle in our
pullback and the next red candle does in
fact close below it that's when I
consider that sellers have taken back
control and that's when we actually
placed this trade as you saw at the very
beginning of the video and if I go ahead
and play forward a bit you can see that
this trade did end up pushing lower and
hitting our Target at around a 2 to1
reward risk ratio now we're on the New
Zealand dollar and we're going to look
at a buy buy is oh my God now we're on
the New Zealand dollar and we're going
to look at a buy example of this trading
strategy and I want you to tell me would
you be looking for a trade right now
hopefully you said no this is one of the
mistakes that I talked about we have a
very shallow pullback no other
Confluence and this is not considered
buying pressure there's a long Wick to
the upside and this is a tiny green body
that's not what we would consider buying
pressure and not to mention the other
confluence Es are not met I'm going to
need a bigger pullback to come down into
previous structure levels and I'm going
to need that to line up with the 50 EMA
to create my perfect pullback
environment and then I'm going to need
buyers to start taking back control
utilizing the rules you learned in the
last part of this video so let's take a
look at what happens next as we push
forward we do get a bit of a deeper
pullback we then get two green candles
we're not really at structure and we're
definitely not at the 50 EMA so this
would not be valid either instead we
push forward and at this point with the
pullback getting a little closer to our
level of structure I would go ahead and
map out that level of structure that I
see will likely coincide with the 50 EMA
so now that that's mapped out we can
push price forward a bit more and right
here do we have a valid bullish version
of the strategy based on what you've
learned today let's talk through all the
conditions are we in a verified uptrend
yes we are that's very easy to see
prices are in fact making higher highs
and higher lows up to this point do we
have a pullback that comes into a
previous level of structure that's been
tested multiple times along with hitting
or getting really close to the blue line
which is our 50 EMA the answer to that
is also yes what does that cover that
covers what we call conditions of our
strategy the next thing we want to look
for is our entry and in terms of this
video what have we talked about being
the entry buyers taking back control
which is going to be defined as a green
candle closing above the last Red candle
of the pullback for a bullish trade so
we have all of that coming together we
have our c and e and our acur MC now we
just got to worry about stops and
targets I didn't talk about that in the
bearish version so I'll do it now in
terms of stops and Targets this would be
the actual reason I would click the buy
button on this particular strategy my
stop loss always goes just below the
swing low wherever that is before our
buyers taking back control and for a
Target most of the time I look for about
a 1.4 to1 reward to risk ratio I then
move my stop loss to break even and I
manag the position as prices head Higher
by moving my stop loss up to the next
swing low as price continues in this
uptrend what that would look like is
move my stop to break even manage my
stop loss as we create new swing lows by
putting that stop loss under those lows
and I do that until we get to the next
major level of structure looking left
for this particular trade as you can see
price did in fact push up easily hit
what would have been our Target
on the screen right now we're looking at
the Aussie dollar tell me is this a
valid trade considering the strategy
you've learned throughout this video
Let's Go a and check off the conditions
are we in an uptrend yes we've created
higher highs and higher lows up to this
point next up are we at a previous level
of structure that's been tested multiple
times Well if I draw a horizontal line
on the screen where price is now yes we
have a level of structure that has in
fact been tested multiple times lastly
for our conditions are we at or close to
the 50 EMA which is our Blue Line yes we
are right on that blue line so now we
have conditions checked off next up is
we're looking for the entry reason which
is buyers taking back control defined as
a green candle that closes above the
last Red candle of our pullback that
would be right here so the candle that
just formed did in fact conclude that
buyers could be taking back control
right now so this is what we would say
is in fact a valid trade based on the
strategy that you've learned in this
video let's put our stop loss right
there we'll go to the 1.4 for like
initial targets and let's click play oh
no what happened a loss yes losses are a
part of trading the way that you get
good at trading the way that you become
a profitable Trader is not by knowing
what the Market's going to do next we're
not trading when we can see what's going
to happen in the future that would be
ridiculous right so how do we be
profitable even with without being able
to tell what the market is going to do
next well we do that by having a
statistic advantage that plays out over
a long period of time so we create a
rules-based strategy or learn one like
you just did that is proven to give an
edge over the market and then we exploit
that advantage over a long period of
time which gives us profits over that
period of time in a very similar way to
the casino always having to get
advantage over the player in 99% of the
games at the casino that's how they make
money the casino doesn't know if they're
going to win or lose that specific hand
of blackjack but what they do know is
that over time they do have an advantage
and they will come out ahead over a
large sample size of blackjack hands
that's exactly what we're doing with a
trading strategy and the way we can see
if we do in fact have an advantage is by
back testing so the next step if this
strategy is something You' like to
utilize in your own trading would be to
go back test this strategy by taking the
rules you've learned for the conditions
entries stops and targets
and back testing that through each
currency pair you would like to trade on
the specific time frame you would like
to trade you'll go back and look over
the past one to five years at every
instance this exact strategy happened
and that will give you the performance
of this strategy or at least the
performance that's happened in the past
and that's the most accurate measuring
stick we have when it comes to trading
based around technical analysis now on
top of doing the back testing to gain
confidence and see if this strategy is
actually something that proves to give
you profits over a long period of time
the next step would be to develop a
solid risk management plan because again
as I just showed you you are going to
have losses no matter what you trade
your ability to deal with those losses
is going to be a defining factor in
whether or not you become a profitable
Trader so in order to deal with those
losses what makes it easier to deal with
losses losing less money what equals
losing less money having better risk
management risking Less on each of the
Trad that you place or at least risking
an amount you're comfortable losing on
those trades and so if you enjoyed this
video and you want some more information
about trading psychology risk management
and other trading systems and strategies
that I personally developed and use
along with having priority email support
which means I'll be answering any of the
questions that you have and if you want
to get two to five email analysis trades
per week where I send you emails of
Trades I'm actually placing then you may
enjoy the TTC 4X University and if you
want to learn all the details to that
all you got to do is click the top Link
in the description or go to www.th
trading channel.com if that's not
something you're interested in no big
deal at all today's video should have
given you all the information you need
in order to put pullback trading Into
Your Arsenal of trading strategies if
you think it did that go ahead and click
that like button for me go and subscribe
if you're new to keep updated about the
content we come out with each and every
week I wish you the best of luck on all
your future trades trade green and I'll
see you in the next video